<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kirk Kittell</title>
    <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/</link>
    <description>kirkkittell.com</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:00:00 CST</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>The Captain's Newsletter, 2026-001</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-11.html#2026-01-11_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-11.html#2026-01-11_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p>Emailed into the void: <a href="/newsletter/newsletter_2026-001.html">The Captain's Newsletter, 2026-001</a></p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Graphs, Pandemic 2</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-10.html#2026-01-10_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-10.html#2026-01-10_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 22:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Previously: <a href="2026-01-03.html#2026-01-03_01">Graphs, Pandemic</a> (2026-01-03)</p>
      <p>I played around a little in Python and made a graph of the Pandemic game board, complete with all the nodes (cities) and edges (city-to-city paths).</p>
      <p>Code: <a href="https://github.com/kittell/kirkkittell.com/blob/main/story/attachments/2026-01-10/pandemic_graph.py">pandemic_graph.py</a>. It's not fancy. It just reads in a .csv file with a list of all cities (and their associated colors) and another .csv file that has the two cities that comprise an edge (path between cities). Then <a href="https://networkx.org/en/">NetworkX</a> builds the graph.</p>
      <p>So, I'll put that graph through its paces later to see what I can learn about the gameboard. Wildly unnecessary, I'm just curious. I feel like there's a way to make a game like this that can build a different sized graph (different set of cities, different connections, etc.) if the (theoretical) player wants to. Again, not necessary, but a toy to play with to see how things work. I don't think I'd ever take it that far, but it ought to be possible to simulate different game plays.</p>
      <p>Beyond analysis, pictures are worth at least a few words:</p>
      <img src="../story/attachments/2026-01-10/pandemic_graph.png" />
      <p>Back in the day, I used to be able to make a more interesting graph output using NetworkX&mdash;maybe using GraphViz somehow?</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Note hoarding</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-09.html#2026-01-09_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-09.html#2026-01-09_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:00:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

      <h2>Note hoarding</h2>
      <p>Taking off from <a href="2026-01-08.html#2026-01-09_01">yesterday</a>... Sometimes I wonder&mdash;useless, and worse I suppose, consciously useless&mdash;where to put things I collect, like lines that I pick up from books. Generally I grab them I hoard them in OneNote, a separate note from each book? Why? Compulsion, I'm sure. Some misguided urge to... ? To hold onto a good thought in case I need it later? To recharge some place in my brain that once found inspiration by stumbling onto the same inspiration again later? It's a mystery. There's no profit in it, for sure.</p>
      <p>Another minor reason, probably best classified under the header Justification, is that it would be interesting to share, for example, that quote so that someone else could enjoy it, or go and read the whole book. (The disservice of grabbing quotes is grabbing them without the connecting tissue, as if a sentence from a book could somehow live well without the rest of its body. Anyway, neither here nor there.) I used to be able to do that when I grabbed the quotes into Evernote, where I could share a public link. I don't think OneNote works like that. I'm not going to worry about it. I'll reinstate an old convention here: kirkkittell.com/ref. Useful? Who will ever know. A nice thing about running a straight HTML site is that I have no idea if anyone is ever here. Zero views? None the wiser. Anyway, I'll collect some notes from <em>The Dog of the South</em>, for instance, in <a href="http://www.kirkkittell.com/ref/reading/the-dog-of-the-south.html">kirkkittell.com/ref/reading/the-dog-of-the-south.html</a>, plus an index or navigation of sorts in /ref and /ref/reading. You're welcome.</p>

      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The Dog of the South</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-08.html#2026-01-08_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-08.html#2026-01-08_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 22:36:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <blockquote><p>I felt queasy. I took two of the orange pills. I can't say I was really sick, unless you count narcolepsy and mild xenophobia, but I was a little queasy.</p></blockquote>
      <p>Charles Portis. <em>The Dog of the South</em>. I can't believe (a) this book exists and (b) I've never heard of it before. Granted, I've been reading it for ages (surely the library will want it back soon) and I have read some Charles Portis before&mdash;only <em>True Grit</em>, which is famous enough to not need introduction.</p>
      <p>But: the dialogue. The patter. I can't imagine writing it. I recognize some of it&mdash;at least the way that people talk past and through each other. I'm from the middle of nowhere, not really from the South, but some of the same tendencies are there. We're not the same people, but we're not that far away. All of the ridiculous dialogue... it's alien, but familiar. I've got maybe 50 pages left to go, and I'm not even sure there's a plot, but I'm keenly plugged into the dialogue. Just give me some more Arkansan babbling, however it comes.</p>

      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhongwensday 2026-W02</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-07.html#2026-01-07_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-07.html#2026-01-07_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:08:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p>Zhongwensday 2026-W02: <b><a href="/zhwotd/w/2026-W02.html">羊 (yáng)</a></b></p>
      <p>A little feature I've been meaning to include with Chinese Word of the Day for years. Finally using the opportunity of a new year to try it out.</p>

      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>RSS</title>
      <link>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-06.html#2026-01-06_01</link>
      <guid>https://www.kirkkittell.com/story/2026-01-06.html#2026-01-06_01</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:39:00 CST</pubDate>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[
      <p>A few notes after reading: Dave Winer, "<a href="http://scripting.com/2025/12/14/142421.html?title=aReallySimpleSocialWeb">A Really Simple social web</a>", <em>Scripting News</em> (2025-12-14)</p>
      <p>Since I started writing again (occasionally, intermittently, &c.) last year, I've just been doing a straight HTML (+ CSS + JavaScript) website. The impetus for that was fairly simple: I had been paying a lot for web hosting over the years and I stopped doing that entirely. I think the folks at <a hr3ef="https://www.siteground.com">SiteGround</a> did a good job, but spending the money was a hard sell at home.</p>
      <p>Incidentally, I also like the attitude of running a site in plain HTML again&mdash;it's just like the 90s again. And I'm one of those people who yells at clouds about how the web used to be Good&mdash;well, if not Good like the quality of the web sites was good, but at least it was Nice. Maybe it was because everyone wasn't online yet, so the network effect of so many people yelling at each other hadn't been activated yet. I'm sure that's part of it. But also there was friction involved in creating and maintaining a site. If nothing else, some of the effort that could otherwise be spent on yelling had to be spent on doing what is now handled by Someone Else, some social media company or WordPress as a backend or whatever.</p>
      <p>So it's nice&mdash;Nice&mdash;to go back to a low quality site again. I'm not sure it will lead to high quality thoughts, but I'll be too busy opening and closing tags to care.</p>
      <p>Anyway, that wasn't the point. The point was: running a web site out of WordPress meant that I had a ready-to-go RSS feed. The software created it for me based on the post I entered into the backend form which was stored off in a database and some tables somewhere. It felt like something technically advanced&mdash;some kind of magic that I couldn't possibly understand.</p>
      <p>I looked into it. So. It's just an XML file with the text/code from the blog posts. Obviously. I'm not sure what I was expecting.</p>
      <p>So, here it is again: <a href="http://www.kirkkittell.com/rss.xml">kirkkittell.com/rss.xml</a>.</p>
      <p>One day I might automate some of this site&mdash;something that will allow easy changing of all the post templates, for example, or copying over HTML blog post articles into the RSS file. Or maybe not. I don't know. There's <em>something</em> satisfying about doing things the difficult, contrarian way, but maybe that's just my problems talking. In the meanwhile I'm going to copy and paste the text, just as Nature intended.</p>
      <p>Related, I guess: this many years later, it's still irritating that Google killed Google Reader... but I didn't realize it was all the way back in 2013 that it got axed. (David Pierce, "<a href="https://www.theverge.com/23778253/google-reader-death-2013-rss-social">Who killed Google Reader?</a>", <em>The Verge</em> (2023-06-30)). I use Feedly's <a href="https://feedly.com/news-reader">News Reader</a> now, which is probably the closest in spirit to Google Reader, but there will always be a Google Reader sized hole out there.</p>
      ]]></content:encoded>
    </item>

    <!-- Add more <item> blocks for each post -->

  </channel>
</rss>
